* [2\. The Mission of the Panasonic Group, and What We Must Do Now](https://www.panasonic.com/global/corporate/about/philosophy/2.html)

        * [10\. Developing People and Making the Most of Their Potential](https://www.panasonic.com/global/corporate/about/philosophy/10.html)

        * [Support for Every Individual: Diverse Work Styles and Work-Life Balance](https://www.panasonic.com/global/corporate/sustainability/diversity-equity-inclusion/support-worklifebalance.html)

Privacy Policy
==============

\- To describe basic policy on personal information protection

\- To describe how we process personal information collected through the use of our website

Personal Information Protection Policy
--------------------------------------

Date of establishment: April 1, 2005  
Date of revision: April 1, 2022

In accordance with the Panasonic Group Basic Management Policy, Panasonic Holdings Corporation ("we") believe that it is important to properly protect and handle the personal information of customers, business partners, and other stakeholders in order to ensure customer satisfaction and trust in our products and services. Therefore, we strive to protect personal information through the policy set out below.

### 1\. Personal Information Protection System

We continuously make officers and employees aware of the importance of protecting personal information and have established and maintain a management system for protecting personal information. In addition, we have established internal rules for the handling of personal information and are conducting proper management of personal information and striving for continuous improvement.

### 2\. Collection and Use of Personal Information

When collecting personal information, we will use lawful and fair means as required by applicable laws and regulations, such as notifying or publicly announcing the purpose of use and other items stipulated by law, or obtaining consent where required to do so. In addition, except as permitted by applicable laws and regulations, we will use the collected personal information within the scope of the purpose of use for which the prior notice or publication was made, or prior consent has been obtained.

### 3\. Provision or Disclosure to Third Parties

We will not provide or disclose personal information to any third party unless we have obtained any necessary prior consents or are otherwise permitted by applicable laws and regulations. We may provide or disclose the collected personal information to third party service providers to the extent necessary to help us achieve the purpose of use. In this case, we will take necessary and appropriate measures to ensure appropriate security management of the personal information provided or disclosed to the service provider.

### 4\. Security management

We will take necessary and appropriate organizational, technical, and physical safety management measures to prevent unauthorized access to personal information, and/or the loss, destruction, falsification, and leakage of personal information (collectively “Incident”). In addition, if we find a problem with respect to our safety management measures, we will identify the cause of the problem and take corrective measures.

### 5\. Establishment of a System to deal with Incident and Response in the case of Incident

We will establish a reporting and response system in order to minimize damage caused in the event of any Incident, related to the handling of personal information. In the event of any Incident, we will investigate the cause and take measures to prevent a recurrence.

### 6\. Compliance with Laws and Regulations

We will comply with applicable laws and regulations related to the protection of the personal information we handle or are responsible for, and strive to continuously improve and enhance our efforts to protect this personal information in response to changes in laws and regulations.

### 7\. Response to inquiries

We respect your rights regarding your personal information and will respond appropriately and promptly to requests of access and correction, etc., from you regarding the handling of personal information in accordance with applicable laws and regulations.

Yuki Kusumi  
President, Group CEO  
Panasonic Holdings Corporation

Any changes to this policy will be made available to you on our website.  
This policy is the personal information protection policy of Panasonic Holdings Corporation. Domestic and overseas affiliated companies have their own protection policies. For details, please refer to each company's website.

Website Privacy Policy
----------------------

Last modified: April 1, 2022

Your Privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy is intended to tell you how we use personal information we collect about you on this website.

This Privacy Policy only applies to the personal information that you provided to us or that are collected through your use of these websites: holdings.panasonic/global/, subdomains of holdings.panasonic, www.panasonic.com/global/, and subdomains of panasonic.com, operated by Panasonic Holdings Corporation (the “Websites”). If you provide your personal information in Panasonic individual services or use other websites operated by its affiliates or subsidiaries, they have their own privacy policies or notices. Please review the individual privacy policies or notices when you use Panasonic individual services or other websites.

Please click on the links below for further information on our privacy practices on this Websites:

1. [Who are we?](#Whoarewe_1)
2. [What is Personal Information?](#Whoarewe_2)
3. [What Personal Information does Panasonic collect about you?](#Whoarewe_3)
4. [On which legal basis do we process Personal Information?](#Whoarewe_4)
5. [Why do we use your Personal Information?](#Whoarewe_5)
6. [To whom and where do we disclose your Personal Information?](#Whoarewe_6)
    1. [Third party recipients of the Personal Information](#Whoarewe_a)
    2. [International Transfer of Personal Information](#Whoarewe_b)
7. [What do we do to keep your Personal Information secure?](#Whoarewe_7)
8. [What are your rights and how can you exercise them?](#Whoarewe_8)
9. [How long do we store your Personal Information?](#Whoarewe_9)
10. [Third party links and products on our Websites](#Whoarewe_10)
11. [Third party features on our website](#thirdpartyfeatures)
12. [Cookies](#Whoarewe_12)
13. [Children’s Personal Information](#Whoarewe_13)
14. [Changes to this Privacy Policy](#Whoarewe_14)
15. [Further Information](#Whoarewe_15)

### 1\. Who are we?

Panasonic Holdings Corporation having its registered office at 1006, Oaza Kadoma, Kadoma-shi, Osaka 571-8501, Japan (“Panasonic”, “we”, “us” or “our”)  
We have a number of Affiliates who can be found here.[https://holdings.panasonic/global/corporate/about/group-companies.html](https://www.panasonic.com/global/corporate/about/group-companies.html)  

### 2\. What is Personal Information?

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Personal Information" consists of any information that relates to an identified or identifiable individual (such as you). For example, information which identifies you may consist of your name, address, telephone number, and online identifier (e.g. cookies and your IP address). Information which does not identify you on its own but that we link to you also qualifies as Personal Information.

### 3\. What Personal Information does Panasonic collect about you?

**_A. Personal Information you provide directly about yourself_**

Some Websites we offer enable/require you to give us your Personal Information.

1. **When you communicate with Panasonic**  
    When you contact us or interact with our customer support representatives, we may collect Personal Information about you, such as your name, mailing address, phone number, email address and contact preferences, and we may also collect information about the Panasonic products or devices you own, such as their serial numbers and date of purchase. We also may create logs/reports that are useful in diagnosing product or application performance related issues, and capture information relating to the issue. We use this information to provide you with customer and product support.
2. **Subscriptions and newsletters**  
    Where you subscribe to our promotional communications and newsletters, we will collect Personal Information including your email address. We will only provide such subscription services to you in accordance with applicable laws and where you have expressly requested us to do so.

[Read More](javascript:void(0);) [Close](javascript:void(0);)

**_B. Information about your use of the Websites_**

We may collect information about your use of the Websites. For example, we collect:

1. **Product/device information** - such as unique device identifiers, IP address, operating system details, and settings of the device you use to access the Websites;
2. **Log information** - such as the time and duration of your use of the Websites, search query terms you enter through the Websites, and any information stored in cookies that we have set on your device (such as your pc, mobile phone or tablet).

[Read More](javascript:void(0);) [Close](javascript:void(0);)

### 4\. On which legal basis do we process Personal Information?

We are not allowed to process Personal Information if we cannot rely on a valid legal ground. Therefore, we will only process your Personal Information when:

1. we have obtained your prior unambiguous consent;
2. the processing is necessary to perform our contractual obligations towards you or to take pre-contractual steps at your request;
3. the processing is necessary to comply with our legal or regulatory obligations;
4. the processing is necessary to protect your vital interests or those of another natural person; or
5. the processing is necessary for our legitimate interests except where they are overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. Examples of such ‘legitimate interests’ include:
    1. to benefit from cost-effective Websites (e.g. we may opt to use certain platforms offered by suppliers);
    2. to protect the security of our IT systems, architecture and networks; and
    3. to meet our corporate and social responsibility objectives.

[Read More](javascript:void(0);) [Close](javascript:void(0);)

### 5\. Why do we use your Personal Information?

We may use the Personal Information we collect for the following purposes:

1. Create an Account/Log in on our Websites - to enable you to create a profile on our Websites and to enable you to log in to such Websites;
2. Registering products/devices - to register you or your device or product for any of our Websites;
3. Provide our Services - to provide our Services or any specific feature that you request, including to enable us to fulfil our obligations under any contract with you. We will show individual privacy policies or notices for each Service where appropriate;
4. Surveys - to ask for your opinions or comments on our Websites and to conduct other surveys;
5. Advertising - for advertising, such as providing customised advertisements and sponsored content and sending you promotional communications;
6. Analysis Purposes - for assessment and analysis of our market, customers, products, devices and Websites;
7. Statistics - to create anonymous, aggregated statistics about the use of our Websites. This anonymised data may be shared with third parties;
8. Service Improvement - to develop and improve new and existing Panasonic products and Websites, recommendations, advertisements and other communications and learn more about your preferences;
9. Customer Support Services - to provide customer support services for your product or device, or to deal with any other support queries you may have;
10. Security - to protect our customers (e.g. to prevent spam or attempts to defraud users of our Websites); to operate and maintain the security of our Websites (e.g. to prevent or stop an attack on our systems or networks); or to protect the rights or property of Panasonic, including enforcing any terms or agreements governing the use of our Websites;
11. Updates - to communicate with you, including communicating with you about your account, profiles or transactions with us, giving you important information about our Websites, sending you notice about any material changes to our Privacy Policy;
12. Corporate Transaction - to manage corporate transactions involving our company including reorganisation, merger, transfer, sale, joint venture, assignment or other disposition of all or any portion of Panasonic's business, assets or stock, including, without limitation, in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceeding.

[Read More](javascript:void(0);) [Close](javascript:void(0);)

### 6\. To whom and where do we disclose your Personal Information?

We will not disclose your Personal Information to third parties for their own independent marketing or business purposes without your consent. However, we may disclose your Personal Information to the following entities:

**A. Third party recipients of the Personal Information**

We may disclose your information to the following entities:

1. **Panasonic Affiliates**  
    We may need to transfer your Personal Information to other Panasonic Affiliates to provide the services you require or any other assistance you request.
2. **Service Providers**  
    We use third party service providers to help us to administer certain activities and services on our behalf, such as fulfilling sending emails and text messages (such as SMS), providing advertisements, analysing usage of our Websites, tracking effectiveness of our marketing campaigns, allowing users to connect to their social network and providing customer support services. We share Personal Information about you with such third party service providers solely for the purpose of enabling them to perform services on our behalf and they will operate only in accordance with our instructions. Here are examples of third party service providers we use:
    1. Email Service Providers – Cloud services are used to assist us in sending emails to you in accordance with your marketing preferences;
    2. Analytics Service Providers – analytics providers are used to assist us in understanding the usage of our Websites, to enable us to improve our Websites. For further information, see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.panasonic.com/global/cookie-policy.html).
3. **Third parties when required by Law or to Protect our Websites**  
    We will disclose your Personal Information to comply with applicable law or respond to valid legal process, including from law enforcement or other government agencies; to protect our customers (e.g. to prevent spam or attempts to defraud users of our Websites); to operate and maintain the security of our Websites (e.g. to prevent or stop an attack on our systems or networks); or to protect the rights or property of Panasonic, including enforcing any terms or agreements governing the use of our Websites.
4. **Other Parties in Connection With Corporate Transactions**  
    We may disclose your Personal Information to a third party (or other Panasonic Affiliate) as part of a reorganisation, merger, transfer, sale, joint venture, assignment or other disposition of all or any portion of Panasonic's business, assets or stock, including, without limitation, in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceeding.
5. **Other Parties With Your Consent or At Your Direction**  
    We may share Personal Information about you with third parties when you consent to or request such sharing.

[Read More](javascript:void(0);) [Close](javascript:void(0);)

**B. International Transfer of Personal Information**

The Personal Information that we collect from you may be stored and processed in your region, or transferred to, stored at or otherwise processed outside your region, including but not limited to Japan or in any other country and where Panasonic or its Affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities.

Where we transfer your Personal Information outside your region, we will ensure that suitable safeguards such as appropriate agreements and mechanisms are in place to help ensure that our third party service providers provide an adequate level of protection to your Personal Information.

[Read More](javascript:void(0);) [Close](javascript:void(0);)

### 7\. What do we do to keep your Personal Information secure?

Panasonic have put in place appropriate physical, technical and organisational measures to keep the Personal Information we collect in our Websites secure. These measures take into account:

1. the state of the art of the technology;
2. the costs of its implementation;
3. the nature of the Information; and
4. the risk of the processing.

The purpose thereof is to protect against accidental or unlawful destruction or alteration, accidental loss, unauthorized disclosure or access and against other unlawful forms of processing.

However, please note that although we take appropriate steps to protect your Personal Information, no website, product, device, online application or transmission of Information, computer system or wireless connection is completely secure and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Information.

[Read More](javascript:void(0);) [Close](javascript:void(0);)

### 8\. What are your rights and how can you exercise them?

1. **What are your rights?**  
    Panasonic will collect, store and process your Personal Information in accordance with your rights under any applicable laws.  
    Your rights include the right to access a copy of your Personal Information, the right to request the correction or the update of any inaccurate Personal Information and the right to object to the processing of your Personal Information under the conditions set out in applicable laws.  
    You also have the right to request the erasure of your Personal Information, and where you have consented to the processing of your Personal Information, you have the right to withdraw such consent at any time (without this withdrawal affecting the lawfulness of the processing prior to such withdrawal). In addition, you also have the right to data portability in certain cases. This is the right to request the return of the Personal Information you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and to request the transmission of such Personal Information to a third party, without hindrance from us and subject to your own confidentiality obligations.
2. **Exercising your rights**  
    If you wish to exercise any of the above rights, please contact us by using any of the communication means described in the individual Privacy Policy or Notice in each Service you provide your personal information.
3. **Complaints**  
    If you are not satisfied with how we process your Personal Information, you may contact us using any of the communication means described in the individual privacy policies or notices or alternatively you may file a complaint with the competent supervisory authority, in addition to your rights outlined above.

### 9\. How long do we store your Personal Information

We will retain your Personal Information for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes for which your Personal Information has been collected as outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required by law. When your Personal Information is no longer required for the purpose it was collected or as required by applicable law, it will be deleted to you in accordance with applicable law.

### 10\. Third party links and products on our Websites

Our Websites may contain links to other third party websites that are not operated by Panasonic, and our Websites may contain applications that you can download from third parties. These linked sites are not under Panasonic's control and as such, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any linked websites and online applications. If you choose to use any third party websites or applications, any Personal Information collected by the third party’s website or application will be subject to any existing privacy policy of that third party. We strongly recommend that you take the time to review the privacy policies of any third parties to which you provide Personal Information.

### 11\. Third party features on our website

Our websites also contain features such as embedded video provided by third parties through their API's that is bound by API's terms of use. Depending on how you interact with these features your information may be shared to these providers. For more information about features' terms of use, please visit each providers' website.

**A. YouTube**  
YouTube API Services are used to play videos on our Websites. Further information on the services and features of the service can be found in [YouTube Terms of Service](https://www.youtube.com/t/terms) and on usage of your information in [Google Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

### 12\. Cookies

This Websites uses cookies to store your preferences and settings and to analyse your browsing experience on our Websites. For further information on what cookies are, how Panasonic and other third parties use them, and for details of how cookies can be disabled, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://www.panasonic.com/global/cookie-policy.html).

### 13\. Children's Personal Information

Panasonic considers a child to by anyone under the age of 16, or such younger age as many be specified by applicable data protection laws. We do not knowingly collect or try to collect Personal Information from or about children without the consent of a parent or guardian. Where we do collect Personal Information from children, we will always use reasonable efforts to verify that consent has been given or authorised by the child's parent or guardian.

### 14\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

Panasonic may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. The “Last modified” at the top of this page states when the Policy was last modified and any changes will become effective upon our posting of the revised Privacy Policy.

### 15\. Further Information

If you have any questions regarding the collection, processing, or use of your Personal Information, please contact us using any of the communication means described in the individual privacy policies or notices in each service.  
If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us by mail below:  
1006, Oaza Kadoma, Kadoma-shi, Osaka 571-8501, Japan

**<For residents of EEA>**  
Panasonic is represented in the European Economic Area (i.e. the European Union, Iceland, Liechtenstein and Norway) for any information protection related matters by its German entity, Panasonic Business Support Europe GmbH, having its registered office at Hagenauerstrasse 43, D-65203 Wiesbaden, Germany.

1. [Home](https://www.panasonic.com/global/home.html)
2. [Privacy Policy](https://www.panasonic.com/global/privacy-policy.html)

[Panasonic Holdings Corporation](https://www.panasonic.com/global/home.html)Copyright © Panasonic Holdings Corporation
